# MARIANO BENEDETTINI

FNGINFFRING I FADER

**9** Bu

Buenos Aires, Argentina

+54 9 11 21569988

mbenedettini@gmail.com

<u>in</u> <u>marianobenedettini</u>

mbenedettini

marianobe.cc

#### **ABOUT ME**

Engineering Leader with a very strong technical background, always hands-on and product oriented. I have experience in a variety of organizations in the US, ranging from small startups (Glide) to Fortune 500 Companies (Compass), plus working as a Software Engineer for ventures all around the globe.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Engineering Manager & LatAm Coordinator Compass (US)

April 2021 - May 2023

I had a double role, first being an Engineering Manager of teams closely related to Glide, supporting a group of 12 people, and then growing the Argentina based team from 10 people to 30+, assembling a recruitment team along the way.

- Created an Android team that built and launched the Glide Android app from scratch.
- Led the implementation of data privacy policies and tools for a successful compliance of CCPA for Glide. This included the complete implementation of DataGrail to help manage and process requests.
- Managed teams related with every aspect of Glide, such as Web, Data and Mobile iOS Engineering to ensure its Business continuity.

# Engineering Manager & Argentina Coordinator Glide (US)

March 2019 - March 2021

Glide is a Real Estate Transaction Management Software, designed to help property managers fill forms, electronically sign documents, ensure compliance and make TCs and Agents lives easier. I weared many hats: Software Engineer, Engineering Manager and Argentina Coordinator.

- I was the first hire of Glide in Argentina and drove the growth of the team up to 10 people.
- I ran a production application with ~6k daily active users with high availability while keeping costs to a budget.
- Engineered different features of the Glide Application using Python, NodeJS and React.

#### Founder & Director

April 2017 - February 2019

Codexia (Argentina)

I Co-founded a small development agency, completely managing two projects including a small team of 3 Engineers. We successfully delivered three customer-facing products based on my proven stack composed of LoopbackJS (back end) + PostgreSQL (database), Angular + Material Design (web front end) and NativeScript for mobile apps when needed.

#### CTO

November 2017 - February 2019

#### TuCuota.Online (Argentina)

I laid the foundations of a system meant to help connect Lenders with Borrowers through retail stores. The proof of concept we came up with made us with the 2nd prize at a competition for Financial startups organized by the Central Bank of Argentina: <a href="http://www.bcra.gov.ar/noticias/El-directorio-y-ganadores-PIF.asp">http://www.bcra.gov.ar/noticias/El-directorio-y-ganadores-PIF.asp</a>

## Senior Software Engineer

PayrollPanda (Malaysia)

I worked on their two products: PayrollPanda and Jibble. Both were based on NodeJS, MongoDB and Backbone. Some important things I've accomplished:

- Simplified architecture with the replacement of a RabbitMQ instance with a much simpler job scheduler (Agenda).
- Introduced automated tests and a reliable build and deploy process to Heroku through Travis CI Server.

#### Software Engineer

May 2015 - March 2016

GreyStar Solutions / Zija (US)

Perl Developer. I fixed bugs, implemented new features and made some recommendations to modernize a rather old-styled MLM (multi-level marketing) system written in Perl and using MySQL.

## Software Engineer

November 2013 - May 2015

Onapsis (Argentina)

Being the frontend architect and lead developer for Onapsis (Yeoman, Grunt, Bower, RequireJS, BackboneJS, jQuery) I created the first version of the modern FE for their main product.

### Software Engineer

May 2012 - October 2013

CuatroGC (Argentina)

Along with three friends we launched a small startup.

I was PM and Developer on a project: Dingo: An online Bingo game engine 100% written in Javascript. Technologies involved: NodeJS, ExpressJS, BackboneJS, Twitter Bootstrap.

# Software Engineer

May 2009 - April 2012

Bet3000 (Germany)

Sports betting company based in Munich, Germany.

- I worked as a Full-stack Engineer. Added complexity because of the big amount of db transactions in real time that the site supports (MySQL) due to live bets (Perl + MySQL + PrototypeJS + jQuery).
- I proposed Chef as an automated tool to manage Kiosk terminals spread all over Germany that we implemented with the DevOps team. Still being used.

#### Different Software Engineer and SysAdmin roles

February 1999 - April 2009

During this period I had 7 different roles where a few accomplishments that stand out are:

- Developed a client-side app for an Internet Kiosk App using Mono (.NET) on Linux
- Migrated root nameserver for the .ar zone from OpenBSD to FreeBSD.
- Deployed Y2K patches on Sun Solaris Servers

# **EDUCATION**

4-year Bachelor in Information Systems at the Universidad Tecnológica Nacional.